Guide to the Emilie F. Miller papers, 1987-1991
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Emilie F. Miller papers
1987-1991
C0048
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
48.0 linear feet (86 boxes)
The Emile F. Miller papers contain materials pertaining to her service in the Virginia State Legislature. Included in the collection are campaign material, subject files, bills and resolutions, correspondence, committee information, constituent files, and information on the Virginia Military Institute controversy.
Miller, Emilie F.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Emilie F. Miller in 1996.
Biographical Information
Emilie F. Miller is a former politician and activist in Northern Virginia and was the first woman senator to represent the Fairfax area. In 1968 she joined the Fairfax County Democratic Committee and served as its chair from 1976 to 1980. In that same year she was hired as long serving Senator Adelrad L. Brault's (1966-1982) legislative aid. Two years later, Senator Brault retired and endorsed Miller's candidacy for the post. Miller's opponent in 1983 was three-term Republican mayor of Fairfax City John W. Russell, whom Miller disagreed with over his opposition to the Equal Rights Act and negative comments about women serving in combat. Miller lost the election by one percent of the vote.
During the interim between her candidacies, Miller remained active in state and local politics. Virginia Governor Charles S. Robb appointed her to the State Mental Health and Mental Retardation Board (1982- 1988). The Fairfax County Board of Supervisors appointed her to the Child Abuse Prevention Task Force (1984-1987). She was also hired as legislative consultant to the Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women (1986-1987). Her activism in mental health, family and community services, and women's rights carried over into her term as Virginia senator.
In 1987 Miller ran for a second time against Russell, and maintained strong support from feminists and was endorsed by the National Women's Political Caucus of Northern Virginia. Narrowly defeating Russell by 180 votes, Miller set off on an ambitious and successful freshman term. She was the only freshman to receive four committee assignments, the only woman to serve on the Education and Health Committee, and was the first Virginia legislator to serve on the Labor Committee of the National Conference of State Legislators.
While a senator, Miller was assigned to four standing committees: Education and Health, General Laws, Local Government, and Rehabilitation and Social Services. She was further assigned to several legislative subcommittees, such as the Parental Drug Exposure and Abuse Committee and the Early Intervention Services for Handicapped Infants and Toddlers Committee.
During her first and second sessions (1988-1989) Miller focused on issues dealing with mental health and substance abuse. She introduced many bills and several were passed. One successful bill allowed future funding for mental health, mental retardation and substance abuse services; another allowed the study of the criminal prosecution of individuals who abuse patients of state facilities for the mentally disabled. One piece of the latter bill established of the State Board of Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse Services, which developed regulations defining abuse and facilitated prosecution of people who abused others with disabilities. Miller successfully amended the state budget by two million dollars for use by mental health services, and ensured that state funding would follow the six-year plan established by the Virginia Department of Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse.
The dominating concern of Miller's 1990 and 1991 sessions was the nationally covered Virginia Military Institute controversy. The U.S. Department of Justice sued the Commonwealth of Virginia for denying admittance to a woman who had applied to VMI. Virginia Attorney General Mary Sue Terry stood behind VMI's decision not to enroll women at the traditionally all-male institution. Miller objected to the practice and considered it sexist and unconstitutional, especially because the school was publicly funded. In response to this controversy, Miller introduced legislation stating that "all public institutions of higher education shall admit qualified students without regard to race, sex, religion, national origin, or political affiliation."
After the VMI controversy, Miller continued to legislate for mental health, women's rights, and family services. Her successful legislation includes the consideration of a defendant's mental health in death penalty cases, the regulation of advertising by licensed treatment facilities for the mentally ill, and authorization for Fairfax County and Fairfax City to regulate child care services and facilities. In addition to this legislation, Miller also introduced legislation that designated April 22, 1990 as Earth Day in Virginia.
Other achievements during her first term include a public-private partnership on pilot projects testing the use of natural gas in Virginia Department of Transportation vehicles, simplified procedures for citizens to obtain government information, and increased civil penalties for zoning code violations.
Miller attempted reelection in 1991, focusing on education and abortion issues, but lost to Republican opponent Jane H. Woods.
Scope and Content
The Emile F. Miller Papers contain materials pertaining to her service in the Virginia State Legislature. Included in the collection are campaign material, subject files, bills and resolutions, correspondence, committee information, constituent files, and information on the Virginia Military Institute controversy.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by topic, including personal files, legislative issues, bills and resolutions, campaigns, and committees.
Related Material
The George Mason University Special Collections and Archives also holds other collections for research on the political life of women in Northern Virginia such as the, the, and the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Miller, Emilie F.
Corporate Names:
Virginia Military Institute.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects:
Mental health services--Virginia.; Women and the military--United States.; Women legislators--Virginia.; Women political activists--Virginia.; Women politicians--Virginia.; Women's rights--United States.
Contents List
  - Abortion-General, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abortion-Guides and Pamphlets 1, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abortion-Guides and Pamphlets 2, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abortion- Parental Notification Correspondence 1, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abortion- Parental Notification Correspondence 2, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abortion- Parental Notification Correspondence 3, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abortion-Press Clippings, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ads, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AIDS, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alcohol- ABC Board, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Association of University Women, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Business Women's Association, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Flag, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Legion, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Mental Health Fund, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arab American List, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Attorney General-Senate Suit, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Babe Ruth Baseball Team- State Championship, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baliles, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Association of Bank Women, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax Bar Association, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Donald Beyer, Jr., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Blake Lane Truck Prohibition, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield- Other, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Boards and Commissions, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Breast Cancer, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Budget Process- Virginia, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Business, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Business and Professional Women, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bypass Round Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Catholic Charities Arlington Diocese, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Catholic Church, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Catholic Schools, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Center in the Square, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Central Fairfax Chamber of Commerce, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Certificate of Public Need, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Charlottesville- Tourism, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environment Council 1, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environment Council 2, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environment Council 3, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Child Abuse (Virginia Treatment Center for Children), 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect (Virginians for Child Abuse Prevention), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Children (Virginia Department for Children), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Children- Virginia Department of Child Protection Priorities, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Child Support Enforcement (Handbook), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chiropractics (Association of Vienna), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Civic Association Letters, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Civic Association- Fairfax City, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Civic Association Lists 1, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Civic Association Letters 2, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Citizen Action, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Citizens for Balanced Growth, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Citizens on Sensible Taxation, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clean Air Act (Federal), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clean Water Action, 33147 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Commendations, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Computer Crime Bill, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Condominium Act, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Conflict of Interest Report, 1976-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Conflict Resolution- George Mason University, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - United States Constitution- Article V, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Consultants, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Contract Services Association, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Courts of Justice Letter, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Supreme Court (Rehnquist's Court), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Crime in Virginia, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cubs- General Media, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cut-Through Traffic, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Daycare (Children Care Facilities), 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Morris Dees (Southern Poverty Law Center), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Democratic Caucus, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Leadership Council 1, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Leadership Council 2, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia 1, 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia 2, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Democrats, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Department of Motor Vehicles, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Domestic Relations, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Downtown Fairfax Coalition, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Drake University (Alumni Magazine), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Drugs (Corporation Against Drug Abuse), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dulles Airport (DART), 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dulles Toll Road, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Education (Board), 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Education and Health Higher Education Subcommittee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Department of Education, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Education Funding for Children in Training Centers and State Facilities Department Study, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Education- Preschool Material for Speech, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Electronic Data Systems, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Equal Rights Act, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ethos Foundation Advisory Committee, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax Center Transportation Association, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax City, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - City of Fairfax Commission for Women, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax City Faxing of Absentee Ballots, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax City Chamber of Commerce, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fairfax County- Public Hearing 1, January 7, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax County- Public Hearing 2, January 7, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fairfax County Council of Parent Teacher Associations, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fairfax County Public Schools, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax County Real Estate Tax Exemption, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fairfax- Falls Church Community Service Board, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fairfax Host Lion's Club, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fairfax Opportunities Unlimited, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Faith Mission Home, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Family Support Subsidy Program, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fairfax County Council of the Arts- Arts for Special Audiences, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Flag Burning, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Form Letters, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - George Mason University- Center for Women in Politics, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Guest Book, 1984-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax County Public Library Guide to the Virginia General Assembly, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Certificates and Framed Items, 1978-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - George Mason University, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General Obligation Bonds- Co-Sponsor, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - George Mason University- Institute for Learning in Retirement, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Goodwin House West- Approval of Crosswalk on South Jefferson Street, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Governor's School- Virginia, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Graduation Parties- Virginia, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Grayson Commission, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Green Virginia 2000- Civic Tree Planting Grant Application, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ground Water, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Group Homes, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gulf Crisis, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Guns- Instant Check Control Law, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Gunston Hall, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Gypsy Moth Suppression, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Head Injury-Head Injury Services Partnership, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Health Care, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Healthcare for All Virginians, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - American Heart Association, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hemophilia, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hermes, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Anita Hill- University of Oklahoma, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hill and Knowlton, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hispania- Latino Quarterly Publication, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Historic Preservation Funding, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Department of Historic Resources, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Association of Homes for Adults, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Horse Center, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hugh L. Gordon- Corporations and Taxes, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Housing, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - High Occupancy Vehicle Lanes, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hunting on the Potomac, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - I-66 Coalition Noise Barriers, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Indians, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Infant Mortality 1, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Infant Mortality 2, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - United States Infrastructure, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - House Bill 335- Insurance 1, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - House Bill 335 Insurance 2, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - John Russell, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Judges, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Legislative Overview, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Leslie Byrne 1, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Leslie Byrne 2, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Leslie Byrne 3, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - House Bill 1071- Limitations on Punitive Damage, 1983-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lobbyists, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Lottery, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - MADD (Mothers Against Drunk Driving), 1982-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Malpractice (Medical), 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - MCV (Medical College of Virginia), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Medicaid/Medicare, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Mental Health, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Mental Health-Children- Out of State Placements, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Mental Health- Public Hearing 1990-1996 Plan, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse Speech, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Mental Retardation Staffing Study, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Merrifield Business Association, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Northern Virginia Minority Business and Professional Association, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Mobil Oil Corporation, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Mortgage Bankers Association, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Model General Assembly, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - National Coalition for Flexible Automated Manufacturing, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - National Association of Retired Federal Employees, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - National Rifle Association, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - National Women's Political Caucus- Virginia, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Labor Committee 1, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures 1, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures 2, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Questionnaire, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Maternal and Child Health, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The George Washington Boyhood Home Foundation, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Task Force on Developmental Disabilities 1, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Task Force on Developmental Disabilities 2, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Task Force on Developmental Disabilities 3, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Women's Network, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NEED- National Energy Education Development, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Emilie F. Miller Newsletter 1, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Emilie F. Miller Newsletter 2, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Emilie F. Miller Newsletter 3, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter (others), 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter Samples- General Assembly, 1979-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Noise Barriers 2, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Noise Barriers 1, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Non-Profit Organizations- Article, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Northern Virginia Board of Realtors, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Northern Virginia Building Industry, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Northern Virginia Community College- State Funding Cuts, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation 1, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation 2, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation 3, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Northern Virginia Planning District Commission, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Northern Virginia Sun Editorial Book, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Northern Virginia Training Center, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Alliance, 1987-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Northern Virginia Youth Symphony Association, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - NOWL- National Order of Women Legislation 1, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - NOWL- National Order of Women Legislation 2, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - NOW- National Organization for Women, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Nuclear Medicines Speakers Bureau, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Nurses Association, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Senate Bill 235- Open Supply and Divorcement 1, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Senate Bill 235- Open Supply and Divorcement 2, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Senate Bill 235- Open Supply and Divorcement 3, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Society of Ophthalmology, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Optometry House Bill and Reports, 1987-1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pages- Capitol Hill D.C., 1990 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pap Smear, Legislative Correspondence, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Parental Leave, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Parental Notification Study 1, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Parental Notification Study 2, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Parents for Compliance, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Pay Equity, 1984-1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Paul VI High School, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, 1976-1982 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings and Articles, 1978-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Peanuts" Veterinarian Bill, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Pensions- Originals to Respond to Inquiries, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Pensions 1, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pensions 2, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Peter Halpin, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Personalities, 1987-1990 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pesticides, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pharmacists, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Phi Gamma Nu, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Phillip Morris- Business and Labor Statistics Virginia, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Planning Districts, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - PODS- Parents of Children with Down Syndrome, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Polls, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Polygraph Tests, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Portfolio of State Issues, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Postal Information, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Prisoners of War/Missing in Action Issue, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Precinct File Form (Original), 1988 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Prescription Drug Program, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Press Release 1991- Mobil Scholarship Fund for Returning Soldiers (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases 1, 1988-1991 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Press Releases 2, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Prevention, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Printing Industry 1, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Printing Industry 2, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Prisons, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Privitization Annual Report, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Proffers Legislation (Comment), 1990 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Project Update, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Prompt-Pay Legislation Report, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Psychologists, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Parent Teacher Associations- Fairfax County Listings, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Public Hearing 1, January 5, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Public Hearing 2, January 5, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Public Hearing Before Northern Virginia Delegation 1, January 6, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Public Hearing Before Northern Virginia Delegation 2, January 6, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Public Hearing Thank You Letters, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Radon (Health Risk), 1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Railroad CSX-RFP, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Real Estate Appraiser Regulations, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Reapportionment- Census Figures/ Restricting Plans 1, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Reapportionment- Census Figures/ Restricting Plans 2, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations 1, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations 2, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)